<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<results><result><quote>...happiness is the highest good, being a realization and perfect practice of virtue, which some can attain, while others have little or none of it...</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>A flatterer is a friend who is your inferior, or pretends to be so.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>A friend is a second self.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>A great city is not to be confounded with a populous one.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>A likely impossibility is always preferable to an unconvincing possibility.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>A state is not a mere society, having a common place, established for the prevention of mutual crime and for the sake of exchange...Political society exists for the sake of noble actions, and not of mere companionship.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>A whole is that which has beginning, middle and end.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Again, men in general desire the good, and not merely what their fathers had.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>All human actions have one or more of these seven causes chance, nature, compulsion, habit, reason, passion, and desire.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>All human actions have one or more of these seven causes: chance, nature, compulsion, habit, reason, passion, and desire.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>All men by nature desire knowledge.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>All paid jobs absorb and degrade the mind.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>All proofs rest on premises.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>All virtue is summed up in dealing justly.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Anyone can become angry. That is easy. But to be angry with the right person, to the right degree, at the right time, for the right purpose and in the right way - that is not easy.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Both oligarch and tyrant mistrust the people, and therefore deprive them of their arms.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Change in all things is sweet.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Character is that which reveals moral purpose, exposing the class of things a man chooses or avoids</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Consider pleasures as they depart, not as they come.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Courage is the first of human qualities because it is the quality which guarantees the others.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Different men seek after happiness in different ways and by different means, and so make for themselves different modes of life and forms of government.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Dignity consists not in possessing honors, but in the consciousness that we deserve them.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Dignity does not consist in possessing honors, but in deserving them.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Education and morals will be found almost the whole that goes to make a good man.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Education is the best provision for old age.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Education is the best provision for the journey to old age.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Even when laws have been written down, they ought not always to remain unaltered.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Evil draws men together.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Excellence is an art won by training and habituation. We do not act rightly because we have virtue or excellence, but we rather have those because we have acted rightly. We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act but a habit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>For the things we have to learn before we can do them, we learn by doing them.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Friendship is essentially a partnership.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Happiness depends upon ourselves.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Happiness is a state of activity.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Happiness is the meaning and the purpose of life, the whole aim and end of human existence.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>He who cannot be a good follower cannot be a good leader.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>He who is unable to live in society, or who has no need because he is sufficient for himself, must be either a beast or a god.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Hope is a waking dream.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Humor is the only test of gravity, and gravity of humor for a subject which will not bear raillery is suspicious, and a jest which will not bear serious examination is false wit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Humor is the only test of gravity, and gravity of humor; for a subject which will not bear raillery is suspicious, and a jest which will not bear serious examination is false wit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>I count him braver who conquers his desires than him who conquers his enemies for the hardest victort is the victory over self.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>I count him braver who overcomes his desires than him who overcomes his enemies.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>I have gained this by philosophy that I do without being commanded what others do only from fear of the law.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>If liberty and equality, as is thought by some are chiefly to be found in democracy, they will be best attained when all persons alike share in the government to the utmost.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>In all things of nature there is something of the marvelous.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>In poverty and other misfortunes of life men think friends to be their only refuge. The young they keep out of mischief, to the old they are a comfort and aid in their weakness, and those in the prime of life they incite to noble deeds.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>In poverty and other misfortunes of life, true friends are a sure refuge. The young they keep out of mischief to the old they are a comfort and aid in their weakness, and those in the prime of life they incite to noble deeds.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>In poverty and other misfortunes of life, true friends are a sure refuge. The young they keep out of mischief; to the old they are a comfort and aid in their weakness, and those in the prime of life they incite to noble deeds.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>In the arena of human life the honours and rewards fall to those who show their good qualities.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is easy to fly into a passion--anybody can do that--but to be angry with the right person and at the right time and with the right object and in the right way--that is not easy, and it is not everyone who can do it.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is in justice that the ordering of society is centered.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is not always the same thing to be a good man and a good citizen.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is possible to fail in many ways...while to succeed is possible only in one way.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is simplicity that makes the uneducated more effective than the educated when addressing popular audiences.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought without accepting it.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought without accepting it.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is the mark of an educated mind to rest satisfied with the degree of precision which the nature of the subject admits and not to seek exactness where only an approximation is possible.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is the nature of desire not to be satisfied, and most men live only for the gratification of it.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is unbecoming for young men to utter maxims.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>It is well to be up before daybreak, for such habits contribute to health, wealth, and wisdom.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Law is mind without reason.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Law is order, and good law is good order.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Let us be well persuaded that everyone of us possesses happiness in proportion to his virtue and wisdom, and according as he acts in obedience to their suggestion.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Liars when they speak the truth are not believed.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Man differs from other animals particularly in this, that he is imitative, and acquires his rudiments of knowledge in this way; besides, the delight in imitation is universal.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Man is by nature a political animal.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Man perfected by society is the best of all animals he is the most terrible of all when he lives without law, and without justice.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Man perfected by society is the best of all animals; he is the most terrible of all when he lives without law, and without justice.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Melancholy men are of all others the most witty.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Men acquire a particular quality by constantly acting a particular way...you become just by performing just actions, temperate by performing temperate actions, brave by performing brave actions.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Misfortune shows those who are not really friends.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Mothers are fonder than fathers of their children because they are more certain they are their own.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Nature does nothing uselessly.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>No great genius has ever existed without some touch of madness.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>No man of high and generous spirit is ever willing to indulge in flattery; the good may feel affection for others, but will not flatter them.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Nor was civil society founded merely to preserve the lives of its members; but that they might live well: for otherwise a state might be composed of slaves, or the animal creation... nor is it an alliance mutually to defend each other from injuries, or for a commercial intercourse. But whosoever endeavors to establish wholesome laws in a state, attends to the virtues and vices of each individual who composes it; from whence it is evident, that the first care of him who would found a city, truly deserving that name, and not nominally so, must be to have his citizens virtuous.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Of all the varieties of virtues, liberalism is the most beloved.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>One swallow does not make a summer.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Patience is bitter, but its fruit is sweet.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Philosophy is the science which considers truth.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Piety requires us to honor truth above our friends.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Pleasure in the job puts perfection in the work.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Poverty is the parent of revolution and crime.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Probable impossibilities are to be preferred to improbable possibilities.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The aim of art is to represent not the outward appearance of things, but their inward significance.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The basis of a democratic state is liberty.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The best friend is the man who in wishing me well wishes it for my sake.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The best political community is formed by citizens of the middle class.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The educated differ from the uneducated as much as the living from the dead.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The gods too are fond of a joke</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The gods too are fond of a joke.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The high minded man must care more for the truth than for what people think.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The ideal man bears the accidents of life with dignity and grace, making the best of circumstances.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The least deviation from truth will be multiplied later.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The least initial deviation from the truth is multiplied later a thousandfold.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The only stable state is the one in which all men are equal before the law.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The ridiculous is produced by any defect that is unattended by pain, or fatal consequences; thus, an ugly and deformed countenance does not fail to cause laughter, if it is not occasioned by pain.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The roots of education are bitter, but the fruit is sweet.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The soul never thinks without a picture.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The true end of tragedy is to purify the passions.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>The wicked have no stability, for they do not remain in consistency with themselves; they continue friends only for a short time, rejoicing in each other?s wickedness.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>There was never a genius without a tincture of madness.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>They should rule who are able to rule best.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>This communicating of a man's self to his friend works two contrary effects for it redoubleth joys, and cutteth griefs in half.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Those that know, do. Those that understand, teach.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Those who educate children well are more to be honored than parents, for these only gave life, those the art of living well.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Those who educate children well are more to be honored than they who produce them; for these only gave them life, those the art of living well.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Those who have the command of the arms in a country are masters of the state, and have it in their power to make what revolutions they please. Thus, there is no end to observations on the difference between the measures likely to be pursued by a minister backed by a standing army, and those of a court awed by the fear of an armed people.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Time crumbles things everything grows old under the power of Time and is forgotten through the lapse of Time.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>To be conscious that we are perceiving or thinking is to be conscious of our own existence.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>To enjoy the things we ought and to hate the things we ought has the greatest bearing on excellence of character.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>To give a satisfactory decision as to the truth it is necessary to be rather an arbitrator than a party to the dispute.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>To love someone is to identify with them.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>To perceive is to suffer.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>To Thales the primary question was not what do we know, but how do we know it.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>We are what we repeatedly do.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act but a habit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, therefore, is not an act by a habit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>We make war that we may live in peace.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>We must as second best...take the least of the evils.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Well begun is half done.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>What is a friend A single soul dwelling in two bodies.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>What lies in our power to do, it lies in our power not to do.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>What the statesman is most anxious to produce is a certain moral character in his fellow citizens, namely a disposition to virtue and the performance of virtuous actions.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>What we have to learn to do, we learn by doing.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Whatsoever that be within us that feels, thinks, desires, and animates, is something celestial, divine, and, consequently, imperishable.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Wishing to be friends is quick work, but friendship is slow-ripening fruit.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Wit is educated insolence.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>With regard to excellence, it is not enough to know, but we must try to have and use it.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Without friends no one would choose to live, though he had all other goods.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Young people are in a condition like permanent intoxication, because youth is sweet and they are growing.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result><result><quote>Youth is easily deceived because it is quick to hope.</quote><author>Aristotle</author></result></results>
